<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eetu Suikkanen</title>
    <link>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eetu Suikkanen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:03:44 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflections, a few months after switching...</title>
      <link>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/reflections-after-a-few-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 14:03:44 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/reflections-after-a-few-months/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-my-change-of-distro&#34;&gt;On my change of distro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So.. In my previous post I was using Fedora as my distribution, and that was because everytime I&amp;rsquo;ve demoed linux for a few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve always tried a new distribution each time and had already tried out &lt;strong&gt;Ubuntu Studio&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Manjaro&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;EndevourOS&lt;/strong&gt;  previously, So I decided to try out &lt;strong&gt;Fedora&lt;/strong&gt; for music production this time around.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been running &lt;strong&gt;Fedora&lt;/strong&gt; on my laptop for a long time now and had used it previously for a server machine that I used to host a &lt;strong&gt;Mumble&lt;/strong&gt; voip server.&#xA;So naturally that made me want to test how easy/hard setting it up for music prodction would be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No coding experience &#43; Co-pilot (what could go wrong.. 😅)</title>
      <link>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/no-coding-experience-copilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 22:38:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/no-coding-experience-copilot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-this-is-about&#34;&gt;What this is about&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the basic version of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Copilot for Visual Studio became free to use, I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying it out by making tweaks to this website I had already previously made.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using Copilot as help, I made this new &amp;ldquo;blog&amp;rdquo; section to the site, and ported over my old blog posts from my wordpress site, just so everything was under one domain name. And for just basic html and css stuff, It&amp;rsquo;s worked great, albeit It got a bit stuck in a loop trying to fix something and It needed the me to tell it what to fix by holding its hand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impressions Composing Jam: Mystery #1</title>
      <link>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/impressions-mystery-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 11:18:28 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/impressions-mystery-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;before-the-jam&#34;&gt;Before the jam&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Haven’t written any music since the last Impressions Jam, so this will hopefully get me to make something 😄, and also a good change to give my linux audio setup a proper test to see how holds up in actual use cases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve used in linux before in a previous Impressions jam, but I had some issues getting my non native sample libraries working without performance issues (EW Play, Kontakt).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Start of the Linux Adventures</title>
      <link>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/start-of-the-linux-adventures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 23:08:43 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/start-of-the-linux-adventures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-setup&#34;&gt;Initial setup&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been playing around with making music on Linux every now and then with some jam projects, but after trying different distributions and learning about what I need to run some of my Windows software on Linux, I finally decided to take the plunge fully and try to swap fully over even if I had to give up some of the orchestral/acoustic sample libraries I couldn’t get running.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impressions Composing Jam: Imagination #2</title>
      <link>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/impressions-imagination-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 11:12:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/impressions-imagination-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Started this jam pretty much the same way I do every time, meaning I started noodling/improvising ideas with piano while looking at the theme prompts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I pretty quickly got a little melodic figure that I liked and then improvised a sketch playing around with it, intending to take a break after that and continuing forward from the sketch.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/images/imprs-imag-2-init-melody.webp&#34; alt=&#34;image info&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ended up getting a bit side-tracked by the Anniversary update to Half Life 2, so didn’t work on the jam for the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impressions Composing Jam: OST #1</title>
      <link>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/impressions-ost-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 11:03:25 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/impressions-ost-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As soon as I saw the picture and text themes, I felt like doing some neoclassical inspired stuff would fit the themes this time around.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been listening to Kirill Pokrovsky’s music a lot lately, so i originally thought about doing something a bit similar to how the music he made for the Divinity games sounded, but after improvising some ideas out in the daw I decided to change over to Musescore and maybe do the whole submission as 1 big suite type orchestral thing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impressions Composing Jam: Ambience 1#</title>
      <link>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/impressions-ambience-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 10:50:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/impressions-ambience-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;time-to-do-some-atmospheric-stuff-i-guess&#34;&gt;Time to do some atmospheric stuff I guess?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Decided to use Cubase for this jam, after trying/learning Reaper for some jams/couple of months now. And in true authentic Cubase style, I managed to get Cubase to crash after only an hour 😂&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Came up with a short 3 note figure/motif pretty quickly after starting to improv some ideas on a piano and started to sketch out some sort of a ambient/atmospheric track around a piano improv/sketch I recorded riffing around the 3 note motif I came up with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying to Establish a Virtual Space</title>
      <link>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/trying-to-establish-a-virtual-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 22:52:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/trying-to-establish-a-virtual-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;trying-to-establish-a-virtual-space-with-reverbs&#34;&gt;Trying to establish a Virtual Space with Reverbs?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Found a &lt;a href=&#34;https://vi-control.net/community/threads/poor-mans-multi-mic-room-hall-reverb.133917/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;forum post&lt;/a&gt; talking about blending dry sounds with other more “wet” sounds by using Convolution reverbs with different IR’s recorded at different spots in a room as Busses you send your tracks to, and then control the send levels like you would a “mic mix” in a sample library.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Took me a bit to understand the basic principles of how it works, but when I got it setup correctly, I found that it worked GREAT! The different “Mics” that you can mix felt much easier to tweak than using a reverbs Pre-delay values and whatnot to try and make things sound farther/closer away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alternative Soundtrack Jam #3</title>
      <link>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/alternative-soundtrack-jam-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:42:17 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/alternative-soundtrack-jam-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;more-nintendo-games-&#34;&gt;More Nintendo games&amp;hellip; 😅&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First thing I did when the jam started, was to play a bit of the theme game i.e Super Mario Bros.&#xA;Played the game for a bit, after which I booted up Reaper, loaded up a NES sound palette using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ymck.net/app/magical-8bit-plug-en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Magical 8bit plug VST&lt;/a&gt;, and started sketching ideas not really being too critical if it fit the theme or not.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After I got a couple short sketches done, I took a break, after which I started working on taking those 3 sketches and tweaking/combining parts from them to make a new sketch based on some feedback I from other people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impressions Composing Jam: Imagination Jam #1</title>
      <link>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/impressions-imagination-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:24:11 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/impressions-imagination-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;deciding-what-to-do&#34;&gt;Deciding what to do&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For this jam I wanted to try and use an old electric organ I recently got for free, so I spent the first day trying different effects and other things to make different sounds out of the organ (by itself the stops on the organ sound like dusty Gameboy Square Waves), but didn’t really feel any of the things I tried so I decided to stop for the day&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alternative Soundtrack - music jam #2: Daily Journal</title>
      <link>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/alternative-soundtrack-jam-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 10:15:06 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/posts/alternative-soundtrack-jam-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-1&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;initial-sketch&#34;&gt;Initial sketch&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First thing I do every jam, is to first get some ideas from the theme while playing the piano, and then record a long continuous take improvising around those ideas. Then I listen back a bit later, and if anything sounds good to me, I start working on from that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the jam started on a Friday for me and I was going to have no time during the weekend, I made a quick sketch of a faux Bossa Nova track, after listening to a track from the Animal Crossing: New Horizons soundtrack.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eetusuikkanen.github.io/about/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a Finnish composer, mostly writing music in varying styles, but might dapple in some other creative endevours every now and then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This site serves mostly as a blog for the various jam events I take part in, and for some occasional posts about other stuff I&amp;rsquo;m playing around/experimenting with, but might include other stuff in the future as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wanna chat? Drop me an &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:eetu.suikkanen.music@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;misc-tracks-from-different-jam-events&#34;&gt;Misc tracks from different jam events&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- ReelCrafter reel: POISON REEL --&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe&#xA;  width=&#34;100%&#34;&#xA;  height=&#34;400&#34;&#xA;  scrolling=&#34;no&#34;&#xA;  frameborder=&#34;no&#34;&#xA;  src=&#34;https://play.reelcrafter.com/embed/209e4bb5-cf2d-447a-992d-bc062fec434e&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;              &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;compilation-of-all-of-my-solo-piano-tracks-and-sketches-from-the-last-few-years&#34;&gt;Compilation of all of my solo piano tracks and sketches from the last few years&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe style=&#34;border: 0; width: 100%; height: 472px;&#34; src=&#34;https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=319963266/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/artwork=small/transparent=true/&#34; seamless&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://eetusuikkanen.bandcamp.com/album/solo-piano-works-2023-2025&#34;&gt;Solo Piano Works (2023-2025) by Eetu Suikkanen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
